<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Boons</name>
    <update version="1.2.2">
      <file name="boons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/revcivic/aurora_elements/master/realdungeonbros/items/boons.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Boon of the Fearless Guard" type="Magic Item" source="The Mad King of Malai" id="ID_TMKOM_ITEM_BOON_OF_THE_FEARLESS_GUARD">
    <description>
      <p>You have grown capable of guaranteeing your strikes at the cost of great danger to yourself. On your turn, you can decide that your attacks (including spell attacks) are guaranteed to hit, but doing this even once causes all enemies to also be guaranteed their attacks hit until the start of your next turn. Guaranteeing your attacks hit this way causes you to not roll for them, ensuring that you cannot get a critical hit. However, enemies still roll their attacks, hitting regardless of their roll but maintaining their ability to critically hit.</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Boon of the Heart of Heroes" type="Magic Item" source="The Mad King of Malai" id="ID_TMKOM_ITEM_BOON_OF_THE_HEART_OF_HEROES">
    <description>
      <p>You can expend all your hit points in a magical explosion healing yourself and any creatures you choose with the hit points spent. Alternatively, you can instead deal damage equal to (Your total hit points)d4 damage to creatures of your choosing, or your total hit points plus 50</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Boon of Giant's Grip" type="Magic Item" source="The Mad King of Malai" id="ID_TMKOM_ITEM_BOON_OF_GIANTS_GRIP">
    <description>
      <p>The strength of giants infuse your hands
				<ul>
					<li>You can wield a two-handed melee weapon in one hand.</li>
					<li>You can grapple creatures up to one size category larger than you.</li>
					<li>Creatures have disadvantage on breaking out of your grapple.</li>
					<li>When grappling a creature, you can use a bonus action to deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Boon of Destructive Touch" type="Magic Item" source="The Mad King of Malai" id="ID_TMKOM_ITEM_BOON_OF_DESTRUCTIVE_TOUCH">
    <description>
      <p>Your body radiates so much malice, that living creatures cannot physically touch you without being harmed. If you make a successful melee spell attack against a creature, they take 3d10 necrotic damage. In addition:
				If a creature makes an unarmed attack against you and you are wearing light or no armor, they must make a Constitution save with a DC equal to 12 + your proficiency bonus. On a failure, they take 2d10 necrotic damage.
				Every round you are grappling a creature, or a creature is grappling you, they must make a Constitution save or take damage, as above.
				If you make a successful unarmed strike against a creature wearing light or no armor, they must make a Constitution save or take damage, as above.
				If a creature succeeds or fails a saving throw from this boon, they are immune to the effects of this boon for one round
				You may re-flavor this boon to instead deal your choice of Fire, Ice, Lightning, Poison, or Radiant damage.</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Boon of The Reaper" type="Magic Item" source="The Mad King of Malai" id="ID_TMKOM_ITEM_BOON_OF_THE_REAPER">
    <description>
      <p>
				<ul>
					<li>Immunity to Necrotic Damage</li>
					<li>Death's Presence<br></br>
						All creatures in a 10ft radius take 2d6 damage per round, radius increases by 10ft every 5 rounds. Damage increases by 2d6 at level 16
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_NECROTIC"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Boon of Carnage" type="Magic Item" source="The Mad King of Malai" id="ID_TMKOM_ITEM_BOON_OF_CARNAGE">
    <description>
      <p>As a bonus action, you go into a frenzy for 1 minute. While in this frenzy, you have advantage on all melee attacks. In addition, when you hit a creature with a melee attack you deal an extra 4d6 damage. When this frenzy ends you gain a level of exhaustion.
			You regain the ability to go into this frenzy after a long rest.
			</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
